<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE refentry PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd">
<refentry id="pybit-web">
  <refmeta>
    <refentrytitle>pybit-web</refentrytitle>
    <manvolnum>1</manvolnum>
    <refmiscinfo class="source">January 2013</refmiscinfo>
    <refmiscinfo class="manual">pybit-web</refmiscinfo>
  </refmeta>
  <refnamediv id="name">
    <refname>pybit-web</refname>
    <refpurpose>buildd server to isuse build jobs to pybit clients.</refpurpose>
  </refnamediv>
  <!-- body begins here -->
  <refsect1 id="description">
    <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
    <para>pybit-web provides a database connection and the controller to
    send messages to pybit clients to create a specific package build
    using the specified version control system. The client feeds status
    messages back to the controller which are displayed via the web
    interface.
    </para>
  </refsect1>
  <refsect1 id="setup">
     <title>Setting up the pybit-web server</title>
     <para>The Debian packaging of pybit-web uses dbconfig-common to 
     configure the database.
     </para>
     <para>For a local postgres instance, choose the unix socket option 
     and the default ident authentication, then postgres as the database 
     administrative user and www-data as the pybit-web database user. 
     You can use whatever name you prefer for the pybit-web database itself.
     </para>
     <para>Note: Ensure that the www-data user is specified or apache 
     will not be granted permission to use the database connection. 
     It's not enough to just set the user to www-data in 
     <filename>/etc/pybit/web/web.conf</filename> - this setting is 
     correct but needs postgres to be configured to allow access to 
     www-data.
     </para>
     <para>Also check that the pybit-web database owner is set to 
     www-data and that all the tables in the database have the owner 
     set to www-data. Use ALTER DATABASE OWNER name TO "www-data" 
     and ALTER TABLE name OWNER to "www-data" if necessary.
     </para>
  </refsect1>
  <refsect1 id="blacklisting">
     <title>Blacklisting packages</title>
     <para>Sometimes there will be packages being committed to the VCS
     with updated debian/changelog files but which either cannot or should
     not be built automatically.
     </para>
     <para>pybit-web supports a postgres table called Blacklist, with
     fields "field" and "regex". Blacklist is used internally by 
     process_job() in controller to determine if certain packages are 
     centrally blacklisted using regexes. If there is a match on the 
     field in question, pybit-web will not issue a build request for
     this package. process_job() is called by both the WebGUI and the 
     VCS hook.
     </para>
     <para>For example "name" and "(.*-dev)" will mean we do not 
     autobuild any development packages, while "vcs_uri" and 
     "(.*/users/*)" will block sources from locations such as 
     /repo/users/jamesb/somebadcode
     </para>
     <para>The controller log will print 
     "BLACKLISTED! - [regex] matches [fieldname]:[data]" 
     if a package is blacklisted.
     </para>
     <para>A 403 will be returned, as well as a False, from 
     process_job to its caller (previously it returned void)
     </para>
  </refsect1>
  <refsect1 id="also">
     <title>See Also</title>
     <para>The pybit wiki has more information on setting up the
     server as well as the rabbitmq server and the watcher.
     https://github.com/nicholasdavidson/pybit/wiki/Server-Setup
     </para>
  </refsect1>
  <refsect1>
    <title>Author</title>
    <para>This  manual  page  was  written by Neil Williams
      <email>codehelp@debian.org</email>
    </para>
  </refsect1>
</refentry>
